export default {
  id: 'mid_6a',
  name: '상용한자(중학6/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '盾', answer: ['방패 순', 'たて', 'じゅん'] },
    { question: '循', answer: ['돌 순', '돌', 'じゅん'] },
    { question: '芋', answer: ['토란 우, 클 후', 'いも', ''] },
    { question: '抗', answer: ['겨룰 항', '겨룰', 'こう'] },
    { question: '坑', answer: ['구덩이 갱', '구덩이', 'こう'] },
    { question: '肌', answer: ['살 기', 'はだ', ''] },
    { question: '飢', answer: ['굶주릴 기', 'う(える)', 'き'] },
    { question: '冗', answer: ['쓸데없을 용', '쓸데없을', 'じょう'] },
    { question: '鉛', answer: ['납 연', 'なまり', 'えん'] },
    { question: '微', answer: ['작을 미', '작을', 'び'] },
    { question: '徴', answer: ['부를 징', '부를', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '懲', answer: ['징계할 징', 'こ(りる)、こ(らす)、こ(らしめる)', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '凡', answer: ['무릇 범', '무릇', 'ぼん、[はん]'] },
    { question: '帆', answer: ['돛 범', 'ほ', 'はん'] },
    { question: '汎', answer: ['뜰 범, 넓을 범', '뜰, 넓을', 'はん'] },
    { question: '恐', answer: ['두려울 공', 'おそ(れる)、おそ(ろしい)', 'きょう'] },
    { question: '嵐', answer: ['남기 람, 폭풍 람', 'あらし', ''] },
    { question: '氾', answer: ['넘칠 범', '넘칠', 'はん'] },
    { question: '範', answer: ['법 범', '법', 'はん'] },
    { question: '厄', answer: ['재앙 액', '재앙', 'やく'] },
    { question: '怨', answer: ['원망할 원, 쌓을 온', '원망할, 쌓을', 'えん、おん'] },
    { question: '宛', answer: ['완연할 완', 'あ(てる)', ''] },
    { question: '腕', answer: ['팔 완', 'うで', 'わん'] },
    { question: '卸', answer: ['풀 사, 도매할 사', 'おろ(す)、おろし', ''] },
    { question: '御', answer: ['거느릴 어', 'おん', 'きょ、ご'] },
    { question: '鈴', answer: ['방울 령', 'すず', 'れい、りん'] },
    { question: '零', answer: ['떨어질 령, 영(0) 령', '떨어질, 영(0)', 'れい'] },
    { question: '齢', answer: ['나이 령', '나이', 'れい'] },
    { question: '柳', answer: ['버들 류', 'やなぎ', 'りゅう'] },
    { question: '仰', answer: ['우러를 앙', 'あお(ぐ)、おお(せ)', 'ぎょう、[こう]'] },
    { question: '抑', answer: ['누를 억', 'おさ(える)', 'よく'] },
    { question: '迎', answer: ['맞이할 영', 'むか(える)', 'げい'] },
    { question: '瑠', answer: ['유리 류', '유리', 'る'] },
    { question: '駆', answer: ['몰 구, 달릴 구', 'か(ける)、か(る)', 'く'] },
    { question: '欧', answer: ['구라파 구', '구라파', 'おう'] },
    { question: '殴', answer: ['때릴 구', 'なぐ(る)', 'おう'] },
    { question: '枢', answer: ['지도리 추, 축 추', '지도리, 축', 'すう'] },
    { question: '繰', answer: ['고치켤 소, 고치켤 조', 'く(る)', ''] },
    { question: '燥', answer: ['마를 조', '마를', 'そう'] },
    { question: '藻', answer: ['마름 조', 'も', 'そう'] },
    { question: '岡', answer: ['산등성이 강', 'おか', ''] },
    { question: '剛', answer: ['굳셀 강', '굳셀', 'ごう'] },
    { question: '綱', answer: ['벼리 강', 'つな', 'こう'] },
    { question: '胴', answer: ['큰창자 통, 몸통 통', '큰창자, 몸통', 'どう'] },
    { question: '洞', answer: ['동굴 동, 밝을 통', 'ほら', 'どう'] },
    { question: '筒', answer: ['통 통', 'つつ', 'とう'] },
    { question: '柵', answer: ['울타리 책', '울타리', 'さく'] },
    { question: '倫', answer: ['윤리 륜', '윤리', 'りん'] },
    { question: '偏', answer: ['치우칠 편', 'かたよ(る)', 'へん'] },
    { question: '遍', answer: ['두루 편', '두루', 'へん'] },
    { question: '幣', answer: ['돈 폐, 폐백 폐', '돈, 폐백', 'へい'] },
    { question: '弊', answer: ['폐단 폐', '폐단', 'へい'] },
    { question: '蔽', answer: ['덮을 폐', '덮을', 'へい'] },
    { question: '偉', answer: ['클 위', 'えら(い)', 'い'] },
    { question: '緯', answer: ['씨실 위', '씨실', 'い'] },
    { question: '違', answer: ['어긋날 위', 'ちが(う)、ちが(える)', 'い'] },
    { question: '乾', answer: ['하늘 건, 마를 건', 'かわ(く)、かわ(かす)', 'かん'] },
    { question: '韓', answer: ['한국 한', '한국', 'かん'] },
    { question: '嘲', answer: ['비웃을 조', 'あざけ(る)', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '傑', answer: ['뛰어날 걸', '뛰어날', 'けつ'] },
    { question: '瞬', answer: ['눈깜짝할 순', 'またた(く)', 'しゅん'] },
    { question: '隣', answer: ['이웃 린', 'とな(る)、となり', 'りん'] },
    { question: '舞', answer: ['춤출 무', 'ま(う)、まい', 'ぶ'] },
    { question: '即', answer: ['곧 즉', '곧을', 'そく'] },
    { question: '既', answer: ['이미 기', 'すで(に)', 'き'] },
    { question: '慨', answer: ['슬퍼할 개', '슬퍼할', 'がい'] },
    { question: '概', answer: ['대개 개', '대개', 'がい'] },
    { question: '祉', answer: ['복 지', '복', 'し'] },
    { question: '肯', answer: ['즐길 긍', '즐길', 'こう'] },
    { question: '企', answer: ['꾀할 기', 'くわだ(てる)', 'き'] },
    { question: '渋', answer: ['떫은 삽', 'しぶ、しぶ(い)、しぶ(る)', 'じゅう'] },
    { question: '雌', answer: ['암컷 자', 'め、めす', 'し'] },
    { question: '紫', answer: ['자줏빛 자', 'むらさき', 'し'] },
    { question: '捗', answer: ['진척될 척', '진척될', 'ちょく'] },
    { question: '渉', answer: ['건널 섭', '건널', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '頻', answer: ['자주 빈', '자주', 'ひん'] },
    { question: '征', answer: ['칠 정', '칠', 'せい'] },
    { question: '症', answer: ['병세 증', '병세', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '錠', answer: ['덩어리 정', '덩어리', 'じょう'] },
    { question: '綻', answer: ['터질 탄', 'ほころびる', 'たん'] },
    { question: '是', answer: ['옳을 시, 이 시', '옳을, 이', 'ぜ'] },
    { question: '堤', answer: ['둑 제', 'つつみ', 'てい'] },
    { question: '促', answer: ['재촉할 촉', 'うなが(す)', 'そく'] },
    { question: '捉', answer: ['잡을 착', 'とら(える)', 'そく'] },
    { question: '婿', answer: ['사위 서', 'むこ', 'せい'] },
    { question: '旋', answer: ['돌 선', '돌', 'せん'] },
    { question: '擬', answer: ['비길 의, 흉내낼 의', '비길, 흉내낼', 'ぎ'] },
    { question: '凝', answer: ['엉길 응', 'こ(る)、こ(らす)', 'ぎょう'] },
    { question: '礎', answer: ['주춧돌 초', 'いしずえ', 'そ'] },
    { question: '仙', answer: ['신선 선', '신선', 'せん'] },
    { question: '峠', answer: ['고개 상', 'とうげ', ''] },
    { question: '拙', answer: ['못날 졸', 'つたな(い)', 'せつ'] },
    { question: '屈', answer: ['굽힐 굴', '굽힐', 'くつ'] },
    { question: '堀', answer: ['흙굴 굴', 'ほり', ''] },
    { question: '掘', answer: ['팔 굴', 'ほ(る)', 'くつ'] },
    { question: '窟', answer: ['구멍굴 굴', '구멍굴', 'くつ'] },
    { question: '坪', answer: ['평 평', 'つぼ', ''] },
    { question: '紛', answer: ['어지러울 분', 'まぎ(れる)、まぎ(らす)、まぎ(らわす)、まぎ(らわしい)', 'ふん'] },
    { question: '盆', answer: ['동이 분', '동이', 'ぼん'] },
    { question: '雰', answer: ['눈날릴 분', '눈날릴', 'ふん'] }
  ]
}
